MAXIMILIANO HERNANDEZ CASTILLO

Software Engineer | Front-End Developer | Back-End Developer



EMAIL

MAXHERNANDEZCASTILLO@GMAIL.COM

WEBSITE

https://max-hernandez.duckdns.org

SKILLS

Problem analysis / solving (Algorithms)

Linux based systems

MacOS

Python

Javascript

NodeJs

PostgreSQL

SOLite

Redis

Django

Celery

ReactJS

Webpack

qUlloR

HTML5

CSS SASS

Redux

Jenkins

Inkscape

Gimp Figma

Git

Docker

Bash sh

English Spanish

PROFILE

Software engineer born in Monterrey, Mexico, with 3 years of professional experience building web applications. Proficient in Python and Javascript; Skilled translating business requirement into software solutions; Extensive experience with Linux systems, being an active user; Essential knowledge in graphic design focused in the design of software graphical interfaces.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering

AUGUST 2009 - JANUARY 2015

Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León - San Nicolás de los Garza, Nuevo León Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering (Ingeniería en Tecnología de Software)

<u>Projects highlights</u>

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning

Coursera

Dec 2020

Credential ID: A8FCSDG5P9M9

See credential

Graphic Design Specialization

Coursera

Aug 2021

Credential ID: K6495WPA96GR

See credential

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Engineer

Crea Libre / Evient, San Nicolas, Nuevo León

June 2017 - June 2019, 2 years

Contributed largely in the implementation of a Web application by heavily participating in the planning of the application's architecture and working on implementing client's requested features.

- Developing new Web features for Front-end / Back-end.
- Building a developing environment for a team to develop and actively provide feedback and test new features using Jenkins, Python and ReactJS tools.
- Involved in planning and decision making for implementing new features.

Software Engineer / Front-End Developer

Wizeline, Guadalajara, Jalisco

January 2022 - July 2022, 7 months

Developing Web interfaces using primarily ReactJS framework.

- Developing front-end interfaces using ReactJS together with NodeJS developing tools.
- Involved in designing new features using Figma tool.
- Involved in Python async task tool maintenance.